ねえ　優ちゃん
優ちゃんはどうして僕を見捨てたの
答えてくれるまで　この夢はずっと続くよ
Why, Yuu?
ここは優ちゃんの中にある闇だから
Why did you abandon me?
そして　僕は…
Until you find your answer,
this dream will continue to haunt you.
僕は君の力
This is your inner darkness.
心が折れそうになったらいつでも言ってよ
And as for me...
僕に身を委ねれば
君の代わりに復讐を遂げてあげる
I am your power.
Call upon me when your spirit is about to break.
ところで優
君ね…
Succumb to me, and I will sate the vengeance within you.
Speaking of which, Yuu,
you're actually...
やっとだ
やっと吸血鬼を殺しに行けるぞ
ミカ
Finally.
The day I slaughter vampires has finally come...
Mika.
I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame
We were all swept away
I'll come and get you; I am always ready to fight
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
There will always be something you cannot control
So don't take all of the blame
We will overcome. Your salvation has begun
We were all swept away
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
No signs, no lights
There will always be something you cannot control
Such a mess all over
We will overcome
Don't kill your hopes
Your salvation has begun
You make me realize who I need
No signs, no lights
Such a mess all over
I'll be there, hold on
Don't kill your hopes
They'll change you somehow
You make me realize who I need
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn
I'll be there, hold on
The shadows appear
They'll change you somehow
Illusions are born
So where are you now?
The fallen angels you run with don't know
I'll reach you by dawn
The shadows appear
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Illusions are born
Torn old sepia photographs show
The fallen angels you run with don't know
Our fragile preious world
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Must discard it, respond to the call
Torn old sepia photographs show
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:鱼子酱&paper   翻译:小悠&冰蝶   校对:夜神&Lucifer   时间轴:阿水   压制:久嘉
Our fragile precious world
Must discard it, respond to the call
Mitsuba's
Squad
My, my, Yuu.
やーやー　優さん
Someone's looking rather spiffy in their brand-new uniform.
制服なかなか似合ってますねぇ
Oh, Shinoa.
シノアか　お前も…
You also...
Yes?
Never mind.
なんでもない
"You look amazingly attractive as well, Shinoa!"
シノアちゃんの制服姿に萌え死にしそうだよー
So, what are you here for?
で　何の用だよ
To give you your orders.
命令を伝えに
Orders?
命令
There are vampires from the Kansai region
planning to retake Shinjuku.
関西方面の吸血鬼たちが　新宿奪還を目論んでいるようです
So if I go to Shinjuku, I can kill vampires?
新宿行きゃ　吸血鬼殺せるってことだな
Please forget about rushing in
with bloodshed as your only goal.
あまり最初から血を求めないでください
We need to strengthen our defenses at Shinjuku before—
戦闘になる前に　新宿の守りを固めることで…
Are you ignoring me?
ちょっと　聞いてます
When am I not?
聞いてませーん
Keep that up, and you'll get swallowed whole out there.
そんなんじゃ壁の外では生き延びれませんよ
吸血鬼殲滅部隊　月鬼ノ組です
We're from the vampire extermination unit,
the Moon Demon Company.
We'll be heading out.
外へ出ます
The Moon Demon Company?
月鬼ノ組…
The one with elite squads?
あのエリートの奴らか
What are they doing recruiting kids?
でもまだガキじゃないか
Keep your voice down, dumbass.
馬鹿　聞こえるぞ
Hear that? They're calling you a kid, Yuu.
ガキって言われてますよ　優さん
No, they're calling you a kid, because you're short.
お前のことだろ　チビだし
Don't be silly. I still have room to grow.
いえいえ　私はまだ成長中ですから
なんせ姉の真昼は　胸がぽいーんの美少女でしたからね
After all, my sister, Mahiru, was a beautiful woman with boobs like you wouldn't believe!
Really? You have a sister?
お前姉貴いんの
If a dead one counts, sure.
もう死にましたが
Well...
なんか…ごめん
I'm sorry.
I think it's a bit too late for that now.
今更そこを遠慮しますか
Now, shall we head out?
さ　行きましょう
In a forsaken, desolate world such as ours...
こんなに醜く荒廃した世界で
there's hardly a single person left who hasn't lost a cherished one.
大切な人を亡くしてない人なんてもう　いないでしょう
Lieutenant Colonel Guren!
グレン中佐　あたしは納得いきません
I refuse to accept this!
Why have I been placed in a squad full of trainees?!
なんであたしが新人ばかりの部隊に配属されるんですか
What's going on?
なんだあれ
I've been in the extermination unit since I was thirteen!
13の時から殲滅部隊にいるんですよ
Who knows?
さあ　新メンバーじゃないですか
A new member, perhaps?
Let's check it out.
降りましょう
Hey, wait up!
ちょっと
Oh, Yuu!
優くん
About time, dumbass.
遅ぇよ　馬鹿優
"Dumbass" yourself, loser.
だーれが馬鹿優だ
What's happening here, anyway?
ってか何あれ
It'd be understandable if I were placed here
to train them as a leader instead.
百歩譲って
あたしが新人教育の分隊長になるっていうのなら分かります
But that midget, Hiiragi Shinoa, with her stupid, smug little smile is the squad leader?!
でも　いっつもへらへらしてる柊シノアが分隊長だっていうじゃないですか
Oh, you all made it.
揃ったな
Aha!
現れたな　柊シノア
Speak of the devil, Hiiragi Shinoa!
That's me!
はーい　現れましたよ　みっちゃん
I know you've been waiting for me, Mitsu.
Damn!
クソ
Play nice, Shinoa.
喧嘩すんなよ　シノア
Mitsuba's gonna be in your squad—
三葉はこれからお前の分隊に入るんだから
もちろん大丈夫ですよ　中佐
No need to worry, Lieutenant Colonel!
The whining of petulant children
is but dust on the wind to adults like me.
私は大人なので
実力のない負け犬の遠吠えなど
You looking for a fight?!
ぶっとばーす
Keep being a pain in the ass,
and I'll throw you both in solitary confinement.
これ以上俺に面倒掛けんなら　独房に入れんぞ
Oopsie.
I'm sorry.
すいません
I'll be heading to Shinjuku via a different route.
俺は別ルートで新宿へ向かう
Before I go, let me make this clear:
別れる前に改めて言っとく
this is your new comrade, Sanguu Mitsuba.
とにかく　こいつがお前らの新しい仲間
三宮三葉だ
Squads of the Moon Demon Company usually move in teams of five.
月鬼ノ組は基本5人1チームで動く
Any fewer, and you'll run a higher risk of being killed by an armed vampire.
5人未満で武装した吸血鬼とぶつかると
殺される可能性が高いからだ
The moment you step outside these walls,
城壁を出たこの瞬間から
you will not fight each other, and you will not fly solo.
どんな状況でも決して仲間割れや単独行動は許されない
Understood?
いいな
You heard the man.
というわけです
Got it, Mr. Hothead?
いいかね　ミスター猪突猛進
No promises there.
約束できねぇな
If there's a vampire right in front of me,
even if I'm by myself—
目の前に吸血鬼がいたら　俺は一人でも…
What do you think you're doing?
何すんだよ
Hm. Nice reflexes.
反応はいいな
I understand, Lieutenant Colonel Guren.
分かりました　グレン中佐
You want me to train him, right?
つまりあたしが　あいつを教育する　というわけですね
So now the troublemaker wants to teach?
問題児が教育ねぇ…
How am I a troublemaker?
あたしのどこが問題児なんですか
Oh, man, everyone here is a pain in the ass.
なーんか　めんどくせぇ奴ばっかだな　おい
Wow, if you think that, then it must be pretty bad.
君月くんがそう思うなら　それは本格的だね
What was that?
なんつった
Nothing, nothing at all!
何でもありませーん
Did it hurt?
痛かった
Hm...
A little.
まあな
Moving on!
とにかくだ　ここにいる奴らがお前らの仲間だ
These guys here are your comrades.
They're more important than even your family.
Protect them with your life.
仲間は家族以上の存在だ
命懸けで守れ
Now, here's your first mission.
んじゃ　初任務を与える
Make your way to Harajuku.
まずは原宿に行け
There's a settlement where the vampires hunt humans, treating them like personal blood bags.
吸血鬼が人間狩りをして　家畜化してる集落がある
Crush them, and free the people.
そこを潰して　人間を解放してから新宿へ向かえ
Then head to Shinjuku.
Wow. It's my first time out ever since I was
taken under the army's custody, but this is...
すごいね
僕　帝鬼軍に保護されてから　外に出るの初めてだけど
ここまでとは…
Before the general ed class, you two were patrolling outside as guards, right?
優くんと君月くんは普通科に来る前
警備兵として外に出てたんだよね
Uh, kinda.
まあな
So what if you've killed the weak Horsemen
of the Apocalypse around the warded barrier?
結界が掛かった城壁周辺の弱い『ヨハネの四騎士』を殺した程度で
Don't get too cocky.
いい気になってもらっては困るな
The Horsemen are incredibly dangerous once you're half a mile past the wall.
そもそも　『ヨハネの四騎士』と呼ばれるバケモノどもは
結界から1キロ離れた辺りから
飛躍的に強くなる
They're nothing like the ones you've fought before!
お前らが戦っていた相手とはまるで別物だ
One little slip means certain death!
ここでは一瞬の気の緩みが死を招く
Don't dawdle, and keep formation!
無駄口たたいて　隊列を崩すな
Stay on your toes if you don't want to die, amateurs!
死にたくなかったら緊張しろ
甘ちゃんとも
Uh, is she okay?
なんなの　あいつ
Isn't she just adorable?
すっごく可愛いでしょう
She's feeling the pressure of having
a bunch of rookies' lives in her hand.
何気に新人の命を任されて
責任感じてるんですよ
It's Harajuku Station.
原宿駅だ
This is the location...
任務地だな
...but where's the settlement?
で　吸血鬼の集落ってのは…
It's a Horseman!
ヨハネの四騎士
Crap!
まずい
Don't move, idiot!
動くな　馬鹿
What?!
Don't break formation!
隊列を崩すな
Help me!
助けてっ
What are you talking about?!
どういうことだ
Hey!
おい　ふざけんなよてめぇ
You can't be serious!
Quiet!
うるさい
What good is this vampire extermination unit
if you can't even save one kid?!
ガキ一人救えなくて
何が吸血鬼殲滅部隊だ
I said, quiet!
黙れ
Let me go!
放せ
This is a vampire's trap!
これは吸血鬼の罠だ
If you try to save her now,
you could jeopardize the entire team!
今あの子を救おうとすれば
我々は全滅の可能性もある
Even if I have to use myself as bait, I'll save her.
俺が囮になってもあいつを救う
You will not! We're going to stand by!
黙れ　待機だ
Then you can stand by on your own!
なら　てめえだけ待機してろ
I'm through living a life
where people need to be left behind!
俺はもう誰かを見捨てて生き延びるなんて　絶対嫌なんだよ
Wait!
待って
優くん
Yuu!
動かないでください
Please stay in position.
吸血鬼が来ます　警戒態勢を
The vampires are approaching.
Be on alert.
あの子は私たちを釣るための餌です
She's bait to lure us out.
Bait? Are you kidding?
餌　冗談だろ
意志を持たないはずの「ヨハネの四騎士」がなぜ吸血鬼に従う
The Horsemen of the Apocalypse have no will of their own.
Why would one obey the vampires?
従っているわけではありません　あの化物は人間だけを襲う
It wouldn't.
Their only instinct is to attack humans,
as if punishing us for overpopulating the Earth.
まるで増えすぎた人間を罰するかのように…
逃げろ
Run!
このバカが
You idiot!
来やがった
They're coming!
分かったか　化物の前に餌を放って助けに来た人間を捕獲する
Get it now?
They toss bait both to lure the monsters out
and to catch humans that come to help.
馬鹿な人間め
Foolish humans.
It's the oldest vampire trick in the book!
吸血鬼のよくやる手だ
距離を取れ
力を貸せ
Give me your strength...
Asuramaru!
阿朱羅丸
なんだ　こいつ
Who is this guy?
百夜
Hyakuya!
Your six is wide open, dumbass.
背中が留守だぞ　馬鹿優
Yoichi, Kimizuki...
与一　君月　お前ら
You guys...
鬼の武器
Demon weapons.
吸血鬼殲滅部隊か
It's the vampire extermination unit.
応援を呼べ　奴らを捕獲するぞ
Call for backup.
We're going to capture them.
してみろよ
Not today, sucker.
そこまでだ　優
That's enough, Yuu.
撤退するぞ
We're going to retreat.
家畜が　逃がすわけないだろうが
Pathetic livestock.
We won't let you get away.
Huh?
てめえ　今なんつった
What did you just say?
引くぞ
Let's fall back.
I won't let you!
逃がすかよ
優さん　ここは敵陣です
Yuu, we're behind enemy lines!
応援を呼ばれる前に離脱します
We need to leave before their backup arrives!
分かったよ
Fine.
一体どういうつもりだ
What were you thinking?!
お前の行動が部隊を危険にさらしたんだぞ
Your actions placed the whole squad in danger!
二級装備の吸血鬼だったから良かったものの　あれがもし
We're lucky that those vampires
weren't armed with stronger weapons!
If they had...
そうだな　お前の言うどおりだ
You're right.
You're absolutely right.
だが　反省はしない　あの子は救う必要があった
But I don't regret it.
We had to save her.
でも　悪かったと思ってる
I really am sorry, though.
殴って気が済むなら　いくらでも殴ってくれ
If it'll make you feel better,
you can punch me all you want.
私はお前のような奴が一番嫌いだ
I hate people like you the most.
お前のような奴が　部隊を全滅させるんだ
You're the ones who lead entire squads to their doom.
あの
Um...
ありがとう
Thank you.
気にすんな　やるべきことをしただけだ
Don't mention it.
We were just doing our job.
もう大丈夫だからね　これからは日本帝鬼軍があなたを守るから
You're safe now.
From now on, the Japanese Imperial Demon Army will protect you!
はい
Yup!
だが　お前は嫌いだ
But...
I still hate your damn guts!
Wha?
まあ　あれです
Well, you know...
ああ見えてみっちゃんも過去に色々あるので
Our little Mitsu has a dark past of her own, so be nice.
やさしくしてあげてくださいねぇ
What do you mean?
何それ
秘密でーす
It's a secret.
一体あの百夜優一郎とかいうのはなんなんだ
The nerve of that Hyakuya Yuuichirou guy!
命令無視に独断専行
Ignoring orders and going off on his own!
あんな奴が月鬼ノ組にいるだなんて　あたしは絶対に認めないからな
I'll never accept him as one of the
Moon Demon Company!
と　激しくぶつかり合った二人でしたが
Despite the two clashing hard,
次第に魅かれ合って恋に
they eventually gravitate toward one another, falling...
落ちるかあ
...not in love!
そんなに優さんが嫌いですか
Do you really hate Yuu that much?
嫌いだね　仲間を危険にさらすような奴は
I do.
I hate people who put their comrades' lives at risk.
昔の自分を見ているようでイライラする　ですか
It reminds you of yourself
from back in the day, doesn't it?
馬鹿が　一人で先走るな　陣形を
Idiot! Don't just mindlessly charge in!
Keep the formation—
仲間が殺されそうなのに　何が陣形ですか
Who cares about formation?!
Our comrade's about to die!
やった
Yes!
馬鹿が
You idiot...
No...
そんな
Hurry up... and go.
速く　逃げろ
あの状況で　あなたに出来ることはなかった
There was nothing you could've done in that situation.
あなたが陣形を崩したから部隊を全滅したわけじゃ
The squad wasn't wiped out because you broke forma—
シノア
Shinoa.
はい？
Yes?
人のシャワー室に勝手に入ってくるな
Don't look at someone while they're showering.
恥ずかしがるなよーん
Come on, no need to be so shy!
W-W-Wait a minute! Stop it!
ちょちょちょっと待て　やめろ
Take that!
女どもは一体何やってんだ
What are the girls doing?
少しだけ君に聞きたい事があるんだけど　いいかな
I have something I want to ask you.
Okay?
うん
君が捉えられていた　吸血鬼たちの潜伏場所についてなんだけど
It's about the place where you were captured,
the vampires' hideout.
でも　答えたくなかったら答えなくてもいいぞ
Oh, but you don't have to answer
if you don't want to. If it's hard for you—
嫌だったら
Ah, I feel so refreshed!
さっぱりした
まったく　シノアは
Seriously, Shinoa...
嫌じゃありません
I don't mind.
助けてもらったお礼を
I want to show my appreciation.
礼なんていいよ　そういうのを気にすんな
You don't need to.
Don't worry about it.
これからお前が毎日笑って元気に生きてくれりゃ　それでいいんだ
If you just live the rest of your life
with a smile on your face, that'll be enough.
Ugh.
ったく
What?!
表参道です
It's Omotesando.
What?
表参道の駅
It's at Omotesando Station.
彼女によると　吸血鬼たちは表参道の地下鉄跡地で
According to her,
the vampires are raising humans at Omotesando Station.
人間を飼育していることが分かりました
いいか
Question.
はい　君月くん
Yes, Kimizuki?
捉えられている民間人はどうする
What are we to do with the captured civilians?
一旦無視だ
We'll ignore them for now.
誰かの心配が出来るほど　私たちに余裕はない
We don't have room to worry about others.
In Return
for Blood
なんだその顔は　不服なら渋谷に帰っていいぞ
What's with your face?
If you have a problem, feel free to trek back to Shibuya.
誰が不服つった
Did I say I had a problem?
俺は吸血鬼を殺せんなら　それで
As long as I can kill vampires, then—
Also, should the vampires be awake and armed,
あと　もし吸血鬼が起きていて更に武装状態だった場合は撤退します
we will immediately retreat.
What?!
また撤退
Retreat again?
ここです
This is it.
正直　黒鬼シリーズを使えるあなた方はなんとかなる可能性もありますが
Honestly, you may be able to manage,
since you have the Black Demon Series.
どうせやるなら　無傷で敵を皆殺しにしたい
But if we're doing this, I want us to crush them and come out without even a scratch.
なので　独断専行は
So don't act on impulse—
I won't.
しねえよ
無傷で奴らを皆殺し　いいじゃねえか
Crush them without even a scratch, huh? I like that.
Then let's move.
では行きましょうか
馴染めた白　鳥がご隅　鼓動獲たツボミも
najimeta shiro torikago sumi
I used to like the light, my corner of the cage
kodou eta tsubomi mo
I'm a flower bud made flesh
置き去り声　眩めた　記憶の影
okizarigoe kurameta kioku no kage
Blinding memories cry after me
I need your blood
i need your blood
You really love 唱える
you read love tonaeru
You speak of love to me
足掻く　Red Light
agaku red light
The red lights dance
嗅ぎ分けた音　音と
kagiwaketa neon to
The neon lamps
こじ開けたReasonが
kojiaketa reason ga
and the madness of the world
ただ平行に並ぶ
tada heikou ni narabu
share a vanishing point
Come on break it down for me!
Come on, break it down for me
come on, break it down for me
A river will flow
a river will flow
KEYがない「欲しい」でも　利害鳴る鈴
My desires remain unfulfilled
key ga nai hoshii demo
rigai naru suzu
A melody of ups and downs
懺悔さえ乾いた　４拍子が　奏でた意図を辿る
rigai naru suzu
zange sae kawaita yonbyoushi ga
Our song follows the sheet of our will,
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
no longer capable of penance
木漏れ日の　赤が　騒ぐ
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
Crimson beams assault my vision
komorebi no aka ga sawagu
次回　終わりのセラフ
Next time, on Seraph of the End:
Dawn of
Extermination
"Dawn of Extermination."